Preliminary Guide to the Gelman Library, Slavic, East European, and Asian Reading Room records, 1962-1995 RG0132
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Office files, 1962-1995; RG0132 Series 2; 36 Linear feet
  - Diplomacy Study: Working group at Georgetown [2/2], 1992 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Conference on Successor States, Ohio University, 06/26/1992 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Copeland Seminar, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Legacies of the Collapse of Communism, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Academic Activities, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - ROTOBO Visitors, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Library Committee [1/2], 1990-1994 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Library Committee [2/2], 1990-1994 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Comments on Manuscripts, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Comments on Manuscripts, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Chemonics, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Applications and Faculty Requests for Research Assistants, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Research Assistantship Information, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Applications and Faculty Requests for Research Assistants, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Applications and Facutly Requests for Research Assistants, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Report on Research Assistants, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Research Assistant Applications, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Files on Research Assistants: Budar, Dorothy, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Sodaro
  - Files on Research Assistants: Dutkin, Raymond Todd, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Kim
  - Files on Research Assistants: Hastings, Juliana, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Millar
  - Files on Research Assistants: Jernegan, Kevin, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Files on Research Assistants: Jia, Hao, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Hinton
  - Files on Research Assistants: Kalinowski, Kathryn, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Agnew
  - Files on Research Assistants: Leng, Tse-Kang, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Files on Research Assistants: Perry, James, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Thornton
  - Files on Research Assistants: Sherman, Karen, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Files on Research Assistants: Sulla, Alexander, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Linden
  - Files on Research Assistants: Wajszczuk, Waldek, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Wolchik
  - Files on Research Assistants: Walker, Peggy, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Reddaway
  - Files on Research Assistants: Chou, Ellen, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Pelzman
  - Files on Research Assistants: Dale, Catherine, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Files on Research Assistants: Holmes, Kirsten, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Files on Research Assistants: Junius, David, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    Rollberg
  - Files on Research Assistants: Loncle, John, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    Atkin
  - Files on Research Assistants: Poling, Naomi, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Work-Study: Timesheets, 09/1992-05/1993 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Work-Study Student Files: Clausen, Robin, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Work-Study Student Files: Klein, Kerry, 1991-1993 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Work-Study Student Files: Harkin, Maureen, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Work-Study Student Files: O'Brien, Kathleen, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Work-Study Student Files: Poling, Naomi, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - George Mason Seminar, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Where are the Young Specialists in the USSR?, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - SIP Papers: "Youth and Truth", 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - SIP Conference China, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - SIP Conference in China, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Sino-American Conference on Emerging Detente, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Soviet Economy Toward Year 2000, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Levine and Bergson
  - Soviet Economic Experiment, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Journal "The Soviet Union", 1990 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Comments on Feige ms, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Workshop:"Changing Patterns in East-West Relations", 04/02/1990 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Conference: US and Europe - Prospects for the 1990s (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - SIP Capstone Conference, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Paper: Finished and Unfinished Business of SIP, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Notes: Rationality and Socialization, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Lecture: The Cost of WWII, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Migration of Money Notes, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Collectivization Revisited, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    Review
  - Wilson Quarterly Letter, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - US-USSR Trade: Lecture, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - SIP: Quality of Life, 1985-1988 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - SIP: Quality of Life, 1985-1987 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - SIP: Quality of Life, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Quality of Life: Lecturer, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Quality of Life, 1970-1980 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    Articles in Russian
  - Ford, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Innovation Workshop, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Book Reviews, 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Stuart Volume: SIP, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Bureau of Labor Statistics Conference, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Trade Policy, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Farewell for Gregory, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - IIE Exchanges, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Slavic Review MS, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Judges Exchange, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - History of SIP, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Paper:"The Impact of TradeandTrade Denial on the US Economy", 1984 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Chayanov Paper, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - International Agrarian Conference: Minsk Paper by Stewart and Millar, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Convergence Hypothesis, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Role of Agriculture in Soviet Economic Development, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Drafts
  - Copeland Proposal, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Chayanov Paper on Peasant Economy, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Publish or Perish, or May the Editor Rest in Peace, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Paper: Soviet Agriculture and its Prospects, 01/1980 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Papers on Dimensions of Planning, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Paper: What's wrong with the Mafiya Anyway, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Rural Transformation in the USSR, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Paper: Grain Embargo, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Paper: 2nd Economy and Queing of Income Distribution, undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Preobrazhensky plus Primitive Accumulation, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Two Views:Millar and Ellman, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - American Perceptions of USSR, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Paper: Economic Convergence, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    In Italian
  - Paper: Primitive capitalist Accumulation, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - US/USSR Agriculture Reading List, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Paper: "Where are the young Soviet Specialists?", 1979 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Book Review: The Industrialization of Russia: A Historical Perspective, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Book Review: Property to the People, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    The Russian Review
  - Book Review: Remaking Russia: Voices from Within, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Slavonica
  - Book Review: Economic Transformation in Russia, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Slavic Review
  - Reviews for Comparative Economic Studies, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Review: in the American Historical Review of Siegelbaum: "Stakhanovism...", 1988 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Review: The American Historical Review: Mark Harisson, "Soviet Planning in Peace and War", 1987 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Review: In Societas of D.J.Male, "Russian Peasant Organization", 1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Reviews of Stewart, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Review: OFER, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Financial Innovation, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Review of Johnson and McConnell-Brooks on Soviet Agriculture in the 1980s, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Review of Davies, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Review of Copeland, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    American Journal of Economics
  - Russian Agriculture and net surplus, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Review of Davies: I and II, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - AAASS Survey: "Opportunities in Soviet and Eastern European studies", 1974 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    Second draft
  - AASS Abstracts: Theme A, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    Environment
  - AAASS Abstracts: Theme B, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    Population
  - Notes:Future Area Studies, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Quantity Theory, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Economic Evolution, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Notes: Transaction demand, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Convergence Hypothesis, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Notes: Keynes' and Say's Law, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Keynes EJ, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Final Draft: Keynes' and Say's Law, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Notes on Say's Law, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Keynes' Notes, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Susan Gross Solomon "The Soviet Agrarian Debate", 1978 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Debate Millar and Nove "Was Stalin really necessary", 1975 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Lecture:"US-USSR Relations", 1971 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Lecture: Gorbachev's Gamble on Youth and Truth, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    Jepson lecture
  - Lecture: Keynes and Say's Law, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Article "Why not a Marshall Plan for the USSR", 1991 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Article "Big Deal, Fair Deal, Little Deal", 1985 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Encyclopedia Article, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Groleir Encyclopedia Article, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Article "Post Stalin Agriculture and its Future", 1979 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Article "What is shock therapy and why has it failed in Russia and other such, 1992-1993 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Article "Institutionalism from a natural Science Point of View", undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - (book) Article on USSR "Encyclopedia Americana", 1990 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Publication "The World Book Encyclopedia", 1990 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Article "Perestroika and Socialist Privatization: What is to be done?", 1990 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Article "The Conversion of the Communists: Gorbachev's Legacy, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Article/Chapter "Daily Economic Life in the USSR", 1991 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Article "Andropov's Alternatives", 1983 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Correspondence and drafts
  - Article "Son of Convergence", undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Article "Copeland on Economics: Institutionalism from a Natural Science Point of View, 1976-1991 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Reply to Ellman article on Agriculture, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Copeland Project, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - ABCs of Soviet Socialism, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    Book, Chapters 4-8 and Reviews
  - Evaluation of CIA Analysis [1/2], 1990-1993 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Drafts, Correspondence, and Notes
  - Evaluation of CIA Analysis [2/2], 1990-1993 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - CIA Review, Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - ACLS, 1992-1995 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - ACLS Constitution and Annual Meeting, 1992-1994 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - ACLS Publications & Education: Sub-Committee of the Board, 1992-1994 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - ACLS Elementary and Secondary School Teacher Curriculum Development Project, 06/19/1994-06/23/1994 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - ACLS Board of Directors Meeting, 10/22/1995 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Book: Social Legacy of Communism (by Millar and Wolchik), 1992 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Book: Social Legacy of Communism (Millar and Wolchik), 1993 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - AAASS 27th National Convention Program Committee, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    Economics
  - AAASS 27th National Convention Program Committee, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Eurasia Foundation, Correspondence, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Eurasia Foundation Report, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    To Appendix F
  - Eurasia Foundation Report, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Appendix G and Questionaires
  - German American Academic Council, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Soviet TV at International Society for the Systems Sciences, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Franz Michael Correspondence
  - Friends of the Institute, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - American: Asian educational Exchange [1/2], undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - American: Asian educational Exchange [2/2], undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Cooperative Programs between International Society for the Systems Sciences and other Institutuions, 1966-1970 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - East Asian Languages and Literature Department, 1965-1985 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - International Society for the Systems Sciences 20th Anniversary, 11/05/82 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - International Society for the Systems Sciences Anniversary File, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Andrei Amalrik, 1973-1977 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Background Information
  - Department of State, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Research Request, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Russian-East European Studies Program: Development, \ ca.1970 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Mihajlo Mihajlov Information, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - International Affairs Course Designation History, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Institution Plan of Organization, 09/1970 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - East Asian Studies Program Development, 1968-1976 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Various Histories of International Society for the Systems Sciences, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Institute Beginnings, 1960-1964 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    London/Woodruff Correspondence
  - Review of International Society for the Systems Sciences [1/3], 1986 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Review of International Society for the Systems Sciences [2/3], 1986 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Review of International Society for the Systems Sciences [4/4], 1986 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - SDS Attack on the Institute - Press Articles, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    Press Articles as well as SDS Pamphlets
  - SDS Attack on the Institute - GW Correspondence, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    GW Correspondence
  - SDS Attack on the Institute - Non-GW Correspondence, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    Non-GW Correspondence but it does contain some GW correspondence.